A Guide to the University of Virginia School of Engineering and Applied Science, Office of the Dean, Office Administrative Files, [1953] 1973-1983
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia School of Engineering and Applied Science, Office of the Dean, Office Administrative Files [1953] 1973-1983
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-11/1/3.872
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student and employee records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.) and the Freedom of Information Act (F.O.I.A.). In addition, the collection may contain confidential donor information.
Acquisition Information
This collection was an archival transfer from the Office of the Dean, 1987 September 4.
Scope and Content
General correspondence and speech files of Dean Lawrence R. Quarles.
Contents List
- Academic Space and Energy Management Offices, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
- Ad Group, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
- Admissions, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- Advanced Level Accreditation, 1979 (Box 1)
  See also Council for Virginia Engineering Deans.
- Alumni/UVA Fund, Dean's Discretionary Fund (Box 1)
- ACE Programming Contest, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
- Apple Project, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
- Applied Math and Computer Science Engineering, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- ASEE ECC, 1977-1982 (Box 1)
- Assignment Sheets (Box 1)
- Associate Dean Transition, 1982 (Box 1)
- Associated Western Universities (Box 1)
- Awards, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
- Boards of Visitors, Educational Policy Committee, March 27, 1981 (Box 1)
- Books and Magazines Ordered, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
- Budget Reduction Contingency Plan, 1982 (Box 1)
- Budget and Funding- School of Engineering, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
- CAD/CAM, Microprocessors, Automated Office, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
  Apple Gift Letters. Apple for Teacher. SEAS Computer User Groups.
- Career Planning and Placement, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
- Calendar, University, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
- Cascade Graphics, 1982 (Box 2)
- Center for Advanced Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
- Chairman's Retreat, May 26, 1982 (Box 2)
- Civil Engineering, 1982-1983, 2 folders. (Box 2)
- Community Colleges, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
- Conferences and Seminars, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
- Consumer Information Officer, 1980 (Box 2)
- Co-operative Degree, 1982 (Box 3)
- Course Offering, 1983 (Box 3)
- Continuing Education for SEAS Faculty, 1981 (Box 3)
- General Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, Miscellaneous N-Z, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
- Course Drop Deadline, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
- Course Initiation Memos, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
- Darden School, 1978-1982 (Box 3)
  See Graduate School of Business Administration previous years.
- DAAD, 1983 (Box 3)
- Drop Date for Graduate Courses, 1982 (Box 3)
- Dual Degrees, 1978-1982 (Box 3)
- Electrical Engineering, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
- Elements of Excellence, SEAS, 1982 (Box 3)
- Eminent Scholars Program, 1976-1978 (Box 3)
- End-of-Course Acknowledgements, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
- "Endangered Species," 1975-1981 (Box 3)
- Energy Policy Study Center, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
- ENGR 109, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
- ENGR 250-Rodman Design Course, 1981 (Box 3)
- ENGR Courses, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
- Engineering Courses for Non-Engineers, 1980 (Box 3)
- Engineering and Applied Science, School of: Graduate Admissions, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
- Engineering ECON Short Course, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
- Engineering Education Program, 1980 (Box 4)
- Engineering Science Program, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
- EIT Examinations, 1979-1982 (Box 4)
- Environmental and Energy, 1981-1983 (Box 4)
- Environmental Sciences, 1972-1979 (Box 4)
- Facilities Engineer, 1978-1980 (Box 4)
- Faculty Employment Opportunity, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
- Faculty Position Allocation, January 1979 (Box 4)
- Faculty Ratings, 1973-1980 (Box 4)
- Faculty Summer Support, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
- Faculty, Up or Out Information for Provost, 1976 (Box 4)
- Faculty Vacancies, 1976-1983, 2 folders. (Box 4)
- Fees, 1981-1983 (Box 4)
- Fellowships and Assistantships, 1981-1983 (Box 4)
- Fellowships, Financial Aid, Miscellaneous Programs of Federal, State, Foundations, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
- Finals, 1981 (Box 4)
  UVA Exercises. UVA/SEAS. SEAS Exercises. Dean's Remarks. Rain Plan.
- Finals, 1982-1983, 2 folders. (Box 5)
- Funding to Maintain Excellence and Flexibility, 1980 (Box 5)
- Gift Summary, 1976-1981 (Box 5)
- Government Relations Task Force, 1982 (Box 5)
- Graduate Matters, General, 1981-1983 (Box 5)
- Graduate Programs, Evening, 1982 (Box 5)
- Greencroft Advisory Workshop, 1981 (Box 5)
- Handicapped, University Committee on and General Correspondence, (1978) 1981-1982 (Box 5)
- Heating Plant, 1979 (Box 5)
- Highway and Transportation Research Council, 1981-1983, 2 folders. (Box 5)
- Highway and Transportation Research Council Board Meeting, January 10, 1983 (Box 5)
  Flow diagram and definitions. Council-wide Effort Levels. Council-wide Research Activities by Program. Program (Group) Research Activities. Program Budget FY 1982-1986.
- Housing, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
- Humanities, 1981-1983 (Box 5)
- Industrial Conferences, 1981 (Box 5)
- Industry Ranking of Computer Units, 1981 (Box 5)
- Information Services, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
- Innovations in Teaching, 1974-1980 (Box 5)
- Institutional Analysis, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
- Interactive Management Center, 1981-1983 (Box 6)
- IBM, August 12, 1982 (Box 6)
- IBM Deans Conference, San Jose, February 22-24, 1982 (Box 6)
- IBM Fishkill Visit, October 7, 1982 (Box 6)
- IBM/MTI School, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
- IBM Proposal, 1982 (Box 6)
- IBM Proposal, 1983 (Box 6)
- IBM Proposal (Hereford Letter), 1982-1983 (Box 6)
- IBM Trip, September 7, 8, 9, 1982 (Box 6)
- International Trade Institute, 1982 (Box 6)
- Institute of Government, 1981 (Box 6)
- ISM, 1979-1981 (Box 6)
- Junior Humanities and Science Symposium (Box 6)
- Lectures, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
- Legislature, 1980-1982 (Box 6)
- Library, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
- Manpower Needs and Related Matters, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  Shortages, Salaries, Degrees, Engineer Manpower Commission.
- Materials Science, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
- Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
- Memoranda, Miscellaneous, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
- Memoranda, Numbered, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
- Microcomputer Course, Spring 1983 (Box 7)
- Microprocessors, 1979-1982 (Box 7)
- National Board of Graduate Education, 1973 (Box 7)
- National Center for Resource Recovery, 1981 (Box 7)
- National Society of Professional Engineers, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
- North Carolina/University of Virginia Subcontract, 1982 (Box 7)
- Nuclear Engineering and Engineering Physics, 1981-1983 (Box 7)
- Oak Ridge, 1981-1983 (Box 7)
- Office Automation, 1980-1982 (Box 7)
- Principal Investigators, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
- Problem Students, Notes on (Box 7)
- Proposal Data, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
- Provost's Office, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
- Purchasing, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
- Quarles Interview by Kauzlarich, May 24, 1973, Permanent. (Box 8)
- Quarles Speeches, (permanent), 1956-1973, 3 folders. (Box 8)
- Questionnaires (Box 8)
- ROMAC Proposal, 1982 (Box 8)
- Registrar Search, 1982 (Box 8)
- Research Triangle Park, North Carolina, 1982 (Box 8)
- SCHEV Education Committee, 1980, 2 folders. (Box 9)
- SCHEV Education Committee Meeting, January 5, 1981 (Box 9)
- Statistical Summary of Activities by Department, 1973-1979 (Box 9)
- Statistics, General, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
- Stockroom Use and Supporting Services, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
- Student Leadership Conference, 1981-1983 (Box 9)
- Summer Session, 1981-1983, 3 folders. (Box 10)
- Surplus Property, 1978-1982 (Box 10)
- Systems Darden Ph.D. Review, 1979-1983 (Box 10)
- Systems Engineering, 1981-1983, 2 folders. (Box 10)
- Three-Two Program, 1981 (Box 10)
- Transportation Centers, 1982 (Box 10)
- Transportation Centers, Council of, 1981 (Box 10)
- University/Industry/Federal Government Relations, 1981 (Box 10)
- University Relations, 1977-1981 (Box 10)
- VAX News, 1980 (Box 10)
- Virginia Center for Transportation Studies, 1982 (Box 10)
- VCU Proposed Master Program, 1982 (Box 10)
- Virginia Engineering Review, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
- Virginia House, 1982 (Box 10)
- Virginia/Japanese Negotiations, 1982 (Box 10)
- Women in Engineering (Faculty and Students), 1980 (Box 10)
- Word Processors, 1982 (Box 10)
- Visiting Professors and Scholars, 1977-1982 (Box 10)